Mikhail Stepanov

Sr. Software Engineer

the.mikhail.stepanov@gmail.com

t.me/go_on_maggot_brain

remote



I am a backend (Java) software engineer with 5 years of professional experience and passion for clean and performant code. I build distributed, robust and fault tolerant services for businesses. I'm also interested in ML (scikit-learn, pytorch) and mobile development (Flutter) in my free time.

work experiences

Total - 5 years

Software Engineer Align Technology inc. | Full-time | 2020 - present Developed new microservices and enhanced backend systems for client-centric applications, such as the web page that manages patient care or API for clinical trials. Assigned as a scrum-master in the team who tracks activity, reviews sprints and release-cycles.

Webinar TeacherGeekBrains | Contractor | 2020 - 2021

Prepared and conducted lectures and homeworks on Java and Spring

Framework. Mentored students throughout the course.

Java Developer Business Environment | Full-time | 2019 - 2020 Developed the backend for an educational online-platform. Designed microservice architecture, participation in task scheduling and code reviews.

Junior Java DeveloperE-COM | Full-time | 2019 - 2019

Developed the backend for the enterprise, document management system for retail. Designed microservices and the architecture.

Performance Test Engineer Aplana Software | Full-time | 2017 - 2019 Made scripts in C, servlets and web services (stubs) in Java. Created test cases, carried out load testing for banking software and analysis of the results.

links



github.com/mikhail-stepanov



linkedin.com/in/mikhail-stepanovv



mikhail-stepanov.com

skills

Hard

Java, Spring, JPA (Hibernate)
PostgreSQL, S3, Redis
Kafka, RabbitMQ, Kinesis
Docker, k8s, Terraform
Microservices, AWS, Heroku
Splunk, Zabbix, Grafana, ELK

Soft

Release Management Task Management Sprint Planning Scrum-master

education

MSc. Business Informatics HSE, Moscow, Russia 2020 - 2022

Exchange, Cyber Security BTU, Cuttbus, Germany 2019 - 2020

BSc. Computer Science HSE, Moscow, Russia 2016 - 2020

I languages

Russian - native English - advanced German - intermediate